Finding Aid for the James L. Britton III Collection
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Stanley Fisk Bryan Collection
1917-1919
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0059
.42 linear feet
Scope and Contents
This collection contains copies of the World War I letters of Captain Stanley Fisk Bryan to his mother, father, and brother. Most of the letters are typed, but several are handwritten. The collection also contains 3 newspaper clippings, 2 pamphlets, and song lyrics all relating to World War I.
- Correspondence – to his mother, Grace Chester Fisk Bryan
  - August 18, 1917
  - October 6, 1917
  - October 22, 1917
  - November 23, 1917
  - December 9, 1917
  - February 12, 1918
  - March 4, 1918
  - April 2, 1918
  - April 26, 1918
  - May 5, 1918
  - May 12, 1918
  - 2 copies, May 21, 1918
  - June 10, 1918
  - June 25, 1918
  - June 29, 1918
  - August 5, 1918
  - 2 copies, September 9, 1918
  - September 15, 1918
  - October 24, 1918
  - October 25, 1918
  - December 11, 1918
  - December 23, 1918
  - December 24, 1918
  - January 25, 1919
  - 2 copies, February 2, 1919
  - 2 copies, March 19, 1919
  - 2 copies, April 7, 1919
  - April 7, 1919
- Correspondence – to his father, Hardy Bryan
  - December 9, 1917
  - November 24, 1918
- Correspondence – to his brother, Hardy Bryan, Jr.
  - 2 copies includes words and music to “Uncle Sam, We’ll Carry On!” – n.d., December 24, 1918
- Correspondence – to W. W. K. Sparrow
  - October 10, 1918
- Newspaper Clippings
  - December 31, 1917
  - n.d. – 2 clippings
- Pamphlets
  - ‘War Words’, A key to the spelling, pronunciation and meaning of many terms brought into public notice by the War. [1915]
  - ‘Brief History of the Fifth Field Artillery, 1st Division, American Expeditionary Forces, 1917-1918.’
- Prayer
  - ‘The Rookies Prayer’ – n.d.